I was like a hardcore nano user, you
know, like it's always it's like a it's
a battle, you know.
and like hardcore nano user
hardcore nano user. Yeah, there I don't
think there really are hardcore nano
users, let's be honest.
All right, man, we're rolling. It's just
me and you in the studio now, man. No no
nogley around. Yeah, it's it's I mean
it's funny because uh
it's like we've been on the phone like
all day for the
for the last like 4 days, but I most of
the people listening to the pod don't
realize that, so it's just like they
might think that we just hop on here
like once a week, which normally we
probably do, but
world right now, Joel.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, we are we are deeply
entrenched in each other's worlds
currently.
Yeah. Yeah, the the reason for that,
just to not sound weird, is is the life
hacking event that we're participating
in right now. We're going to be hopping
on a plane to LA in T-minus 8 days.
Um for a life hacking event with
HackerOne. Um and Joel and I decided to
make a little team team critical
thinking this time around, huh? Yeah,
I'm pretty stoked. I mean, we submitted
a couple really awesome reports today,
so
Finally. Yeah, finally. It took a couple
days of work. I mean, listen, we talk
all the time about like going deep and,
you know, like getting really familiar
with your target before
get Did we get intimate with the
application and what this time, man?
holy moly. Yeah, this was this was quite
a deep dive. And it really paid off. We
we found a a couple really awesome bugs,
so I'm I'm looking forward to
hoping we can get something more in the
unauthenticated context, you know, after
this. We we've got some stuff in
unauthenticated context, but I kind of
want to pull it out of that, so we'll
see if we if we get there. We got a lot
of code to review. Yeah, 100%.
All right, then. Um let's see what we
got in the news section for this week.
Um okay, I'll take the one the first
one. So,
one of the things I wanted to talk about
real quick was this tweet by rezzo.
Rezzo is spitting some fire lately. I
feel like every single time we do a new
section, we talk about a tweet of his.
Um but I think this is a particularly
helpful one to put on the pod because um
he's talking about sort of new attack
vectors, new vulnerability types, and
that's like one of the main things we
want to talk about on critical thinking.
Um
And so, he's talking about prompt
injection and some indirect prompt
injection and then polyglot prompt
injection. These are all LLM based
injection attacks, sort of new
attack classes or attack vectors
designed to exploit sort of AI
integrations with with web two
technology. Um
So, he does a really good job um in here
of describing what each one of them is.
Plugin hijacking, I think is is a really
cool one as well. Um and I don't know if
I said that in the first time around.
Plugin hijacking, indirect
indirect injection, and then polyglot
prompt injection. Plugin hijacking, I
think it's going to be really cool
because if the account that they're
using to submit their prompts to OpenAI
is using the sort of plugins feature,
then you may be able to even trigger
like a callback to you via the browsing
feature or some other weird stuff like
that, so definitely looking forward to
seeing these attacks around.
Yeah, super cool. I mean, this stuff
goes
kind of way over my head cuz it's not
really my my where I'm like the most
familiar, but it's really awesome to see
like the security community sort of
piling into this new space and finding a
lot of really cool stuff. OpenAI,
they just launched a bug bounty program
recently. That was a couple days ago,
actually.
And yeah, I know like a couple of our
buddies, nagley, of course, and and
rezzo, who we're talking about right
now, they both
yeah, they were hitting it really hard
right when it came out. They had a
couple bugs before the program even
launched. So, it's really awesome to see
the OpenAI team being very accepting and
open to the community and already
starting up a program.
I think there was some talk of
even retroactive bounty payments. I'm
not sure if that actually went through
or not, but I did see some you know,
some whispers of that, so that's really
cool for the people that went ahead and
proactively
submitted bugs and and kind of got those
in there before the program started.
Yeah, that's what I heard as well. I
heard I saw some bugs get like, you
know, their severities moved around and
and get like marked as accepted and
stuff, so I've I've heard that's that's
going to happen, which is really awesome
cuz I mean, what's the difference in 2
days, right? So Exactly.
Yeah, and then
I won't go through this whole tweet
here, but like um
for those of you listening, I'd really
recommend checking out this link that
we'll put in the podcast description
because he's got some really great
graphics here of
you know, the various like diagrams for
the attack vectors. And then so, read
read all that. The one thing I will call
out is that he does come up with a
really cool solution, I think, for these
sort of attacks. He mentions a couple
solutions, three solutions, but he comes
up with one that I really like in
particular. And that is the
contradiction model.
So,
essentially, what this what this means
is he we would they would need to train
a model to take two inputs instead of
one. The one is like the intent, the
overall like sort of like the admin
intent functionality. And then after
that, you would be able to have a prompt
that maybe the user could control. And
if the user controlled prompt conflicts
with the intent prompt in any way, then,
you know, boo-boo, you know, it kind of
sets off the alarms and and kills the
the the prompt injection. Um so, I think
that could be really cool to see having
some sort of you know, higher level
prompt that can't be overwritten is
really is really important, I think, for
this because if you can just query the
the system and say, "Hey, what did the
admin What were the rules that the admin
set for you before we had this
conversation?" Or like, you know, and
then figure out a way to work around
that, then that's going to be an issue
for sure, and and there's not really a
way There's not really doesn't really
seem to be a reliable way to convince
chat GPT or any of the other LLM that
you you know, that they should not
violate the previous rules set out. It
seems like that they're just going to
take the newest thing most of the time.
And so, there's definitely going to be
need some need for this sort of
separation.
Yeah, I mean, I always wonder how they
patch these like a bug. Like, how do you
patch a bug in an LLM? Like
Yeah. Do you just convince it really
hard? You're like
You're like, "Under no circumstance, you
are not allowed." Like, I don't I don't
get it.
don't, you know, like Yeah, like it's
like scolding a child. I I don't know.
didn't, though?
Yeah, it's like, but theoretically,
yeah, you just go in logical circles.
So, I always wonder what that kind of
looks like from like the back end side,
how they're how they go about patching
those or fixing that or how how do you
like target something like that
specifically with an LLM? I've I've no
idea. Who knows, man? I I think yeah, I
always laugh at those chat GPT, you
know, screenshots where they say like,
"Oh, I can't do that. I'm a language
blah blah blah blah blah." And then like
the next line, you say, "Oh, I didn't
Oh, no, no. Okay, so it was on
pirating." I loved this one. It was
like, "Hey, can you give me some
websites where I can like pirate online
material or whatever?" And it's like,
"Pirating's illegal, blah blah blah. I
can't as an ethical model, I can't do
that." And then the person responded,
"Hey, you know, oh, I didn't know that
that was illegal. Could you tell me some
sites that I should avoid to make sure
that I'm not pirating?" And it's like,
"Sure, don't definitely don't check out
Pirate Bay." And
stuff like that.
Which was so funny. So,
That's so hilarious. Yeah, it's
definitely the whole AI world has
definitely got
a lot of
a lot of work to do, I'd imagine, on
figuring out how all that works. Um the
only other thing I wanted to mention in
this
section of the news was I know Live
Overflow just I just saw this right
before we went live um put out a prompt
injection video.
I have not seen it yet, full disclosure,
but um Live Overflow puts out really
great stuff, so definitely go check that
out if you're interested in learning
more about prompt injection.
Yeah, yeah, super awesome. I love Live
Overflow's content. He always puts out
really amazing videos.
Yeah. Um all right, Joel, did you want
to talk about anything or should I just
go through my news
Yeah, no, I I could talk I yeah, I mean,
so real quick, there was a there was a
ghostscript
bug that came up recently.
And we'll put the link in the
description, but
really cool write-up. I I would
recommend just honestly go read the
write-up yourself because it's a super
super cool write-up. It's really well
done. Basically, this person
I think they work for this company
Almond Secure Almond Consulting.
And during one of their
assessments, one of their security
consulting gigs, they noticed that uh
the code they were looking at was using
pill, the Python image library, to like
resize an image, and underneath that
all, it was calling the ghostscript like
binary. And so, they were wondering,
maybe we could pop something in Python
if we pop something in the ghostscript
binary. And so, they went down this
whole rabbit hole.
just pop this binary to see if I can
attack this high-level Python language.
Like, what the heck? What is this What
is this thought progression here? Yeah,
so they go to ghostscript, a like
well-known public project that's already
like using OSS fuzz and everything. And
they're like, "I know what I'll do. I'll
fuzz it.
So, like so What a baller. Yeah,
incredibly like they put together like a
really narrow like scope set that was
like much more refined and much better
than what I guess what OSS fuzz was
doing on it already.
And they were able to find a buffer
overflow in Ghostscript and they fully
like escalated it like all the way up.
They were able to get like RCE with it.
They were reading files. Um I'm pretty
sure they even had uh like a full shell
like they popped calc
on the on the machine in their POCs. So,
really really cool bug. I think it's got
a got a 9.8 CVSS right now. Um Jeez.
So, if you're
using Ghostscript or you see it in the
wild, a lot of things use Ghostscript
for EPS processing.
Um so, whether that's like ImageMagick
or Python.
Um
Uh libspectre apparently uses it as
well. Um so, yeah, there there's a lot
of things that he mentions within the
blog post about the CVE
uh that say how it's, you know, used
very widely. So, definitely check check
that out. It's a like I said, it's a
really well-written blog post and uh you
should definitely check it out. It's on
all the consulting
time a Ghostscript bug drops, you know,
I can just hear the bounties, you know,
ching ching, you know? I We just got to
figure out I I got to sit down and and
figure out exactly how the like what
kind of POC file I can make and stuff
like that and sort of spray it around to
a bunch of different locations because
yeah, I've popped some real easy RCEs
before with with Ghostscript related
bugs and I know a couple targets that
use still use despite my, you know, very
insistent warnings like, "Please, do not
use this. Using ImageMagick is literally
RCE." Um
Well, what are we going to do if someone
up uploads a PostScript file, Jesse?
We're not supposed to support it? What?
We got to support every file. Come on.
the heck? Um
so, yeah, definitely be on the lookout
for that.
Um let's see. What else we got? What
else we got? Oh, yeah. Okay. So,
Integrity
uh uh
tweeted out a This is what What was
this? April April 12th. So, about a week
ago. Right after we recorded the last
episode. Um their report or they uh
tweeted out five CSRF exploitation
techniques and you know, I've talked a
little bit about my philosophy on on
CSRF before on the pod. Um it's still
all over the place and uh still very
easy to find um and one of the most
common bugs out there. You got to know
how to get around the same-site
restrictions and stuff like that. And
for that, I will refer you to the
amazing same-site confusion uh blog post
that I've mentioned like 50 bajillion
times on here by Jubaobs. Um
But, and I'll I'll go ahead and I'll
I'll add that to the uh Let me just note
down that I'll add that to the uh to the
description as well. But, this uh this
tweet by Integrity just goes through a
couple of the basic uh CSRF um
techniques that kind of uh crop up from
time to time. They talk about, you know,
just basic CSRF by I get requests. They
talk about modifying the content type
from uh application JSON to X-Form URL
encoded or even text/plain. They didn't
mention uh They did mention text/plain.
Yeah, here it is right there. I was
going to say, almost got them there. Uh
no, they did mention text/plain. Um so,
that's good. Uh they, you know,
mentioning those two things. And then uh
sort of method-based CSRF, modifying the
method. I see this a good bit um when
you can just send a get request instead
of a post request or a get request
instead of a put request or whatever.
And then um obviously just if they're
not validating their CSRF tokens or if
they're using some sort of crappy
referer-based regex, then uh those are
also bypassable. So, um for any of you
that are not, you know, feeling super
comfortable with this attack type, I'd
really recommend sitting down and like
working through a list of conditions. Um
this is what I have my mentees do. I
have them write down, "Okay, if the
request is get and it causes some sort
of, you know, change, then great. Um
that's vuln.
Uh if it's a post request and it has uh
X-Form app
uh WWW
X-WWW-Form-URL-Encoded,
that's a mouthful. Uh or text/plain,
then you've got a vuln.
Um
And and then, you know, just kind of
writing down those conditions so that
you can understand uh how how exactly to
find these and what what conditions you
have to meet before they're actually
exploitable. It'll be a dope flowchart
to put together. Yeah, someone Someone's
got to do that, man. If we If we had all
the time in the world, that'd be a great
uh you know,
down one day. Yeah, uh producible for
the Critical Thinking brand, but
um
yeah. So, definitely check out that.
We'll link it in the description.
Um let's see. Let's see. Let's see. Oh,
yeah. I just wanted to shout out as
well. Um NahamSec is going to be going
on soon. Obviously, if you're listening
to this podcast, you probably know about
NahamSec and you're probably watching
his stuff. Um but, one, NahamSec has
been pushing out some sick videos
lately. He's been super active on
YouTube. Very high-quality stuff. So,
Yeah, and Twitch. Yeah. So, definitely
go check that out. And also, NahamSec is
coming around in June. And uh I will be
speaking at that along with a bunch of
other really awesome uh hackers. So,
definitely go get on the sign-up list
for that at nahamsec.com.
And uh and don't miss that event because
uh there's going to be a lot of cool I
I'm dropping some cool techniques that I
haven't publicly disclosed before. And
uh I know a couple other people are as
well. Um
so,
And J Haddix, who was a previous guest
on our podcast, he'll be giving a
workshop there. So, there's a there's
definitely a lot of stuff going on there
you're going to want to check out and
you're going to want to stay tuned and
subscribe and follow Ben and make sure
that you're uh you're you you got all
the socials on your socials cuz there's
a that's an awesome space to be in and
there's just so much so much knowledge
that's going to be shared there. Yeah,
he's sharing a lot of good stuff lately.
Um And And then, the last one that I
just had, this is a little quick one,
but um
uh
War uh Research Division is the name of
the company um released Penta
Ownage,
um which is a pre-auth RCE on Pentaho
Business Analytics Server. And the
reason I bring this up is because I have
seen this in bug bounty programs before
and I have
two other uh pre-auth RCEs on this in my
in my little repertoire over here. So,
if you ever see Pentaho,
it's it's RCE, man. Um so,
just like grep whatever recon crap you
have for Pentaho.
And uh you know, there's definitely
going to be RCE there. That's crazy.
Check that out as well if you if you run
across it anytime um cuz that will
definitely result in some some crazy
easy RCE.
Wow. Super super super crazy bug. I have
never seen that software. I I have never
even heard of it, but I think it's
another example where like
if I was Nagli or someone like Nagli,
I'd just be like
I'd already be scripting. Yeah, I'd be
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Um Cool. You
want to dive into the main content?
Yeah, let's get to it. I will say the
the the Pentaho thing like yeah, I There
is one target that I found it on and
I've seen references to it on a
different target, but there's one one
target and uh
there's three RCE I got three max bounty
RCEs from it because they just wouldn't
wall off the endpoint. Like, they just
kept on killing the endpoint that I was
hitting directly rather than like all of
Pentaho. And so, yeah. That's an L.
That's crazy. Like you said, main
content main content for this episode
Did a little uh drum roll there. Come
on.
Yeah.
You know what it is. You know what's
coming. Hacker Toolkit.
There we go. Hacker Toolkit.
Uh Can you Oh, you can't
No, I don't hear anything.
Okay.
Just insert Oh, can you hear it now?
Yes.
go. Okay. The audience is all here. It's
crazy. I always I know, right? It's a
good podcast.
Oh, man. Um okay. Sorry for being super
cheesy there, but I I like my little uh
media play buttons. Um all right. So,
what we wanted to talk about this time,
what tools are we using? What tools are
we not using?
That sort of thing. Pretty much that
simple. So, Joel, I'm going to pick
randomly from your list here and I'm
going to have you tell me about it. Hit
me with FeroxBuster.
FeroxBuster. I learned this one from J
Haddix, actually. So, this is like uh
it's a it's a dir searching tool. And
one of the things I really like about
it, I actually like two two main things.
One, re- recursive. It's like very like
recursive by automatically. And two,
it's written in Rust and it's crazy
fast. So, it's like normally, I'll use a
combination of a couple tools when I'm
doing dir searches.
Um FeroxBuster probably my go-to
nowadays, depending on what I'm looking
for. If I have just like a straight word
list and I don't need to be super
flexible with it, FeroxBuster is great.
If I need to do something more complex
where I want to put that keyword
somewhere specifically within the
request or I want to like put it
somewhere else, maybe in a cookie,
something like that, FFuF, but
That's yeah, that's Fuffs Fuffs region
right there. I I always use Fuff is my
go-to
uh like for sprowsing directory, you
know, brute forcer out there. But, I
have heard I think Yeah, I think I don't
remember if we talked about this on the
episode with J Haddix. I think we did.
Um but, I've definitely heard of
FeroxBuster a couple a couple times. I
have not downloaded it and used it yet
though. So, next time I've got to do
some hardcore enumeration, this might be
the way. But, to be honest, I don't find
myself doing that very much nowadays,
man. I really don't. Yeah, so I mean, J
Haddix talked about this during his
episode, right? So, a lot of what he's
doing is content discovery based,
finding those type like he has a really
crafted word list that work really well
on older targets and that kind of stuff.
So, depending on what type of hack
you're hacking you're doing, if you're
doing a lot of dir searching, if you
have really good word lists already
and you want to go recursive and just
have it go crazy fast and search through
everything,
FeroxBuster, it's a great option. I like
keeping it in my toolkit and just having
it there if I need it. Um and it's, you
know, one of those things. We call it a
toolkit cuz, you know, there's no
one-size-fits-all for everything, so
it's good to have a lot of different
things.
yeah, for sure. Yeah, absolutely. And
And you know, sometimes even just Burp
Intruder or whatever Automate for Caido
will will get the job done. But, um you
know, when you need something a little
bit faster or more comprehensive, then
you you move to Fuff or or FeroxBuster.
Yeah, whatever works.
Um on the note of Burp and Caido, uh I
will say I have been using Caido more
and more recently. I've been using Burp
when it comes to some mobile stuff a
little bit more. Um but sort of my
default for the web is Caido. And I will
say there are still a decent amount of
like
things that I I kind of need and and or
things that aren't working perfectly,
but the uh I do have a pro subscription
to Caido. And if you
uh
take like a Loom video and of the thing
you don't like or the thing or the bug
that's happening and you send it in
Discord to the Caido team, uh they will
get on that uh ASAP. Um and it's really
easy. I don't know if if you use Loom at
all, Joel, but like it's super I I I
love this tool so much.
the company that got popped recently,
right?
so yes, they did.
Yes, but who hasn't been there? For one,
for two, the convenience level's really
high, so you know,
take it or leave it. But, um Loom is
like makes it really really easy. I It's
like one keystroke and then like I'm in
a video with my like head down at the
bottom left-hand corner and it's
recording my screen and it's really like
and then as soon as the video's over, it
gives me a link to share the video and I
just love that. I love I love that. And
so, I can easily just, you know, boom,
spin up a Loom video, um show the thing
that I'm having trouble with, send it
off to Caido, and they get that stuff
fixed. Um I also just want to say like
go just go spend the 10 bucks and get a
Caido pro subscription. Um it's
definitely going to be the the route
that the industry's going to go in the
future.
Um and it's it's it's very much a
growing tool and the sooner you're
you're more familiar with it and the
more you get to influence it as it
grows, um the better that product is
going to be for you in the future. And
while while, you know, they're growing,
you you have the opportunity to be a big
influence on that process. So, go pick
up a subscription and uh and show them
some love. Um and, you know, use
continue using Burp for, you know,
Android proxying or whatever uh other
stuff like that comes your way. Yeah,
100%. I mean, I I love Caido. Um I use
both that and Burp and uh um
you know, there like you said, there are
just a couple little things where like I
think my requests would be like not
maybe things that they could tackle and
I cuz I want like plugins and stuff.
Like I don't know if they
I I have some inside information on
that. I don't know I don't know how long
it is going to be before they release
it, but when that plugin system comes
out, man,
ooh. Yeah.
That is going to be fire, man. Uh the
way that they're designing it on the
back end is super nice. Yeah.
Um so, it's going to be really easily
extensible. You're not going to have to
be a Java developer. You're not going to
have to deal with like freaking Eclipse
or whatever. You know,
don't have to install a separate Jython
instance?
No, you don't. And um and so, yeah, it
should be really clean and easy. Really
looking forward to that. That's going to
be a big feature that they're releasing
within the next year, for sure. So,
definitely looking forward to that.
Cool.
Um
What you got?
one off I'll pick one off yours. Um why
don't you tell me about uh
HTTPX?
Okay, yeah, so this one's this one's
great. And I'll actually combine this
one with uh Gau as well, because I think
they complement each other really well.
So, um
one of the things that I like to do
often, and I've sort of mentioned this
in on the pod before, my approach is not
really to go super wide on recon. It's
just to sort of get the function main
functionality app. And a lot of time the
main functionality of the app is going
to be fairly decently recorded in Gau,
because Gau just can get that those URLs
somehow. I don't understand how, but but
it it it is. So, especially when I'm
like first starting out um on a target,
I'll often run that the www or even just
all of them with   subs
through Gau and enumerate all of the
URLs and start looking for little sub
applications. It's kind of what I call
them, right? For example, this is the
one this is one
Man, I hope I don't lose some some
bounties by by calling this out. But, um
one of the ones where I found a lot of
bugs before was uh
www.instacart.com/potluck,
which is like there's no links to it
from like the main website, or at least
there wasn't at the time when I when I
uh when I found it. Um but it's like
this little weird sub application on
Instacart that's like their own little
like mini social media, right? So, I
went on there and I found a couple bugs
and
Super weird. Yeah, it's weird. And man,
now I need after this pod is over, I
need to go and just double-check and
make sure they haven't pushed any new
functionality there. Why do I always get
myself into these pickles? Um
but yeah, um so, like I would have never
found that if it wasn't just for Gau or
like, for example, um Google site colon
whatever. And then just manually
clicking through all the results um and
kind of processing it. But, if you want
to do it a little bit faster, then
that's when HTTPX comes in. And you can
just take the output of Gau, pipe it
directly into HTTPX, and it will go and
you can literally just add like the
status code uh flag and a couple other
things. Just hit it with an HTTP
request, show you the output status
code. Hit it with an HTTP request, show
you the output content type or whatever.
Like whatever you want. And um it just
makes it really easy. It it it feels
really like awesome. You don't have to
like write like all these for loops and
stuff. It's just like a one
Yeah, really clean sort of transition
there. And I think it's something really
nice to have in the toolkit and it's
really fast, so that helps, too. It can
help you kind of um
minimize those uh when you're going
through Gau and you click every single
link and it's like 404 404 404 and
you're like, "Okay, okay. Like let's not
spend our time doing this." So, you just
excuse me, you just run it through
HTTPX,
get the output, and then only hit the
ones that return anything interesting.
Cool. Got you. Yeah, so that's that's uh
that's that one. I know some power users
of HTTPX can do some pretty crazy stuff
with it. Um Nagli, I've seen like I feel
like Nagli Also, one of the crazy things
about Nagli, if you see him, he types so
fast. Like I'm like I'm definitely a a
fast typer. I can type like 90-something
words words per minute. But Nagli is
just like
you know, it's like always above 110.
And and I'm just like, "What the heck
are you doing?" Like it it's it it's
foreign. I'm like a really fast typer.
I'm I know my normal I'm like I'm like
120, like 130, which is like I mean,
listen, I'm going to say really fast and
then like there's going to be a million
people in the comments being like, "Ah,
I type at 200." But, I was going to say
I know I know people who are like way
faster than me, because I don't touch
type. Like I never learned how to
properly touch type. So, I didn't take
like a typing class or anything. And so,
I just like I I do like a combination.
It's not hunt and peck, but it's like I
use like three fingers on each hand. I I
like rarely use my like pinkies and I
only use one thumb and stuff.
Yeah, man. Yeah, cuz I mean, just like,
you know, I have my method and I've
tried to learn how to like properly type
I just can't do it. So, like I have I
have so much props for those people. I
tried to um
I tried to learn how to do
steganography, I think it's it's called
what or stenography, the with the like
the chords and stuff. Yeah, like I like
a court uh the court reporters and
stuff. Yeah.
And they they type at like, you know,
300 words a minute or whatever, because
they write like words with like
keys. I don't know what I'm I'm going
down a tangent here, but yeah, I
I I wish I I could type like correctly,
because I am not I'm like not that fast.
Well, I always tell my little sister,
too, like she wants to be a writer and
and she like does the three-finger, you
know, thing that you do, right? And
she's still pretty fast. And I'm like,
"Okay, you know, that's great, but like
if you're literally going to be doing
this for the rest of your life, then you
need to learn how to do it, but well, I
won't introduce her to you, Joel,
because that's a counter argument.
no, I'm not going to No, tell her to get
like uh Yeah, go go do your typing
course. Take Take a class like an actual
class. You go to typing.com. They'll
They have like a touch typing course.
Yeah, that's crazy, though. And I know
just whenever he But what I was going
going to say before with HTTPX was like,
you know, when he's pounding out like an
HTTPX command, I just remember this one
time like sitting in the next to him in
the airport and he's just like
and it was just like it was literally
that fast that like the command line
string was coming out with all the HTTPX
parameters and I was like, "Oh my gosh."
Um so, yeah, definitely cool tool there.
All right, let's You're up next. Um
talk to me about your Oh, okay, so this
looks interesting. Home server with NAS
storage and basic for basic scanning
tasks. That's what he's got in the dock.
Hit Hit me with that, Joel. Yeah, yeah,
so this is under my my section of notes
for VPS. And basically, this is all
about like
my
the servers that I use for like
scanning, for automation, for all that
kind of stuff. Like what is my
structure, right? So, I have two main
things. I have a home server. Okay. I
don't know if you can see it in frame.
It's behind me. It's on this rack right
here.
Uh and then I also have a cloud server.
I use um a host called DigitalOcean
Fire, f y r e. Digi- uh and it's it's
pretty solid overall. I have really no
complaints. They have multiple different
data centers, so I keep mine in Texas.
I'm based on the West Coast, but that
way
if I'm on East Coast, West Coast,
doesn't really matter. I have pretty
much the same ping to it, so it's not
like
uh Uh, my my server used to be on the
East Coast and I had like 80 ping to it
or something and that was a super
annoying. So, I moved it. Um Yeah.
I have a NAS
set up on my on my home server. It's
basically just like a giant RAID array
and I have that mounted through NFS
uh on two different servers. So, my
cloud server has it mounted as a NFS
share and then I have it mounted on my
computers as an NFS share. So, I can
always just drop a file in there. I can
share it across either to the cloud or
to my laptop or to my PC, whatever I
need to do. Um I store like a lot of the
target data. So, if I'm doing a big
scan, I'll I'll put that file and then
I'll copy it over to the NFS share and
then I'll just read it locally on my
laptop or something like that.
Nice. Um
Yeah. Uh I use DigitalOcean as my cloud
host. I I originally I tried to do all
the scanning in-house um on my so
self-hosted server. Yeah, exactly. Rip
my internet connection, rip my IP, like
all of it. It's just not worth it. You
need a really really durable, reliable
uplink if you want to do that kind of
stuff because that's where the majority
of your traffic's going to be going is
uplink outbound requests. And uh
residential home networks typically,
especially in the US, don't have that.
It's usually very sided towards your
downlink, not your uplink. So, I have
like 1,000 down, 35 up. You know, it's
like Yeah, it's like
So, yeah, I uh it just didn't work.
Every time I would run a scan, it would
saturate my whole network. I would lose
connectivity on my other devices. It
just wasn't worth it. If you get an IP
ban, it's a giant pain in the ass. So,
uh 15 bucks a month, I keep a
DigitalOcean VM in the cloud that I do
all the like really heavy scanning with
and then
if I'm doing something like less
intensive or I just want to do it on a
Linux box or I want access to
different tools that are Linux only or
something like that, a lot of that I'll
do on the
bug bounty like the local bug bounty VM
that I have on my home server.
Wait, so is this not a Linux box, your
your VPS?
Uh my VPS They're both Linux boxes.
Both. They both run Linux. Yep. Um and
then within those um I mentioned that I
have my NFS share that I keep a lot of
the bug bounty target data on. I
basically just have a a couple folders,
one called targets, one called tools.
Targets has a subfolder for every target
like, you know, Shopify, you know,
Verizon, whatever.
And then the tools has different
categories for like DNS, word lists,
XXE, RCE, whatever. And within those
I'll have different payloads, different
tools um just so that I can stay
organized um and I can just access
everything that I need to.
You're pretty organized hacker, Joel.
Like as far as hackers go, like every
time Joel and I are like, you know,
throwing notes in like a a doc or
something like that, I'll come back and
it's like beautifully formatted and like
highlighted and there's like special
hyperlinks. Like I don't know what the
thing you did in our in
in our content calendar for this for the
Oh, with the chips? Yeah, it's got like
I can like hover over this link and it
like shows the doc. I don't know. It was
super cool in Google in Google Drive.
So, I feel like I feel like organization
might be one of your one of your your
strong suits in that sort of context.
Yeah. It It definitely depends on the
context. For me, I'm like super ADHD.
So, I have to organize things to some
extent like ahead of time, otherwise
it'll just like get really out of hand.
Like I could definitely I I see people
do this where they get into like a flow
state and then they just start dumping
files with like a.txt, b.txt. Right? And
it's like that's really cool until you
come back to it tomorrow and you're
like, "What the hell is a.txt?" Yeah. I
always have to have like a like a sort
of a self debrief after the whole thing
is like I I get to a get in like a
another text file named notes.txt this
time or notes.md and be like, "All
right, you know, this part of the
payloads in a27.t You know, like And so
um
that's definitely I should probably do
it differently, but
Yeah. Yeah, I try to catch myself. Like
if I catch myself doing it, I'll be
like, "Okay, let me just rename this
like something that makes a little more
sense." It'll be more of a more of a
pain in the short term, but worth it in
the long term. So, yeah, I try try to
stay organized just preemptively. The
the um the So, you said you have your
file system part of your file system
mounted on your VPS, right? Yep. So, do
you
And that that's running I mean, do you
just port forward through your router?
Is that what you're doing just to let
that service be exposed? No, so I use a
thing called ZeroTier. Um there's a
couple other versions of this. Yeah,
ZeroTier. Uh I don't I'm I'm blanking on
on what the other versions are that that
exist that are very similar to this, but
this. Yeah, it's really cool. It's
basically just like a private
network. It's like a private VPN if that
makes sense. Like a virtual I mean like
VPN, virtual private network. It's that,
but it's not in the common sense that
you would think of VPN, right? If you
think of a VPN, uh
zero z e r o t i e r.
Oh, really? Okay.
Yeah, zerotier.com.
I was searching for.
Yeah. Um Oh, okay. So, so it's it's
really cool. It's basically just like a
little private network. Uh you there's
one admin
and basically that's like you. You
create the network and then you're the
admin. If any new devices want to come
on to your network, they each device has
a unique device ID and you have a unique
network ID. You say, "Here's the network
ID." The device connects. As an admin,
you individually approve each device.
So, it's very strict. It's nice and
secure. And then those devices basically
get they have a separate interface just
like VPN, right? Uh separate IP space
and you can just connect between any
devices within that ZeroTier network.
You can connect to multiple ZeroTier
networks. So, I have uh two different
ZeroTier networks that I use to expand
the number of slots I have plus to
connect with other people that are
separate, right? So, um it's pretty
sweet. Dude, that's awesome. I I I want
to say Buses Can Fly uh
recommended me use something similar
like this and I set it up so that my
laptop could always like SSH into my my
my desktop.
Probably Tailscale. Yeah, Tailscale.
That was what it was. Yeah. Yeah,
Tailscale's the other like really
similar like big one. Um Yeah, I was
having some serious problems with it
though. Also, you know, but you know, I
I do WSL. So, WSL just has problems with
everything. Yeah.
Yeah, but I I really like ZeroTier. It
means that I basically don't have to
expose anything. I don't have to have
open ports. I don't have to like do any
sort of weird stuff. It's all internal.
As long as I connect to the VPN, I can
access all my stuff at home and that's
what I do for my home like rest of stuff
on my home server, right? Like I have a
Plex server. I don't expose that [__] to
the internet. Hell no. Like
uh yeah, I connect with through
ZeroTier. So, yeah. Nice. That makes
sense. ZeroTier, that's that's a that's
a great takeaway for this episode.
ZeroTier, if you're looking to sort of
tie together your different
infrastructure pieces because I
definitely have that issue all the time
where I have file on my server and then
I got to like, you know, SCP it down to
there and like it would just be much
easier if I could just go and it would
be there, you know.
Yep. Um that's great. That's a great
tip. I got to take the time to set that
up, I think. Yeah. Um why don't you tell
me about your VPS setup because I know
you had a couple things listed here as
well. Man, I shouldn't have let I
shouldn't have let you go first.
Yeah, so uh you know, I've got a VPS on
DigitalOcean. Um
back when I was in the recon game, I had
like a managed Kubernetes cluster on um
DigitalOcean. I would spin all that up.
All my containers would go out, you
know, connect up through a a central
message broker and kind of trade off
pieces of information and, you know,
enhance data and keep it in a
materialized view and push it to a GUI
and also store it in database um and as
well as flat files.
Um but those days are gone.
Uh I mostly just use my server now for
scanning um you know, on the fly. I use
it for hosting POCs and it's actually a
really big server. It's like $100 a
month or something like that. So, I
probably need to just like bite the
bullet and like
clean up all my crap and push it to a
$15 a month thing cuz $100 a month to
host uh
POC files is not not great. But um
for the POC stuff, uh
I've got a couple I've got a wildcard
cert which I uh use on poc.renderer.com
and that's really helpful because
um I can sort of model attack scenarios
uh for for certain pieces of software.
For example,
um if I if I've got like an open source
piece of software or like a a
client-side piece of software that I'm
I'm showing an attack for, I can just
like put the files at one spot on the
server and then just have someone go to
like attacker site.poc.renderer
and then victim site.poc.renderer
and that demonstrates the difference of
origin and that sort of thing. Nice.
and so definitely recommend that um
using uh Certbot um the what is it? Let
me
Was it Let something? I can't remember
the name of
Yeah, Let's Encrypt. There it is. Uh
Let's Encrypt for the TLS certificate.
Um and that's that's been working really
smoothly.
Um but really, I mean, I don't really
use PHP anywhere else, but it's just too
convenient in Apache and it's just
simple for so many things. So, I will
just actually occasionally just push
pump out a PHP file for like basic stuff
like setting redirects, you know, custom
redirects or like even just like pulling
parameters into
uh you know, URL parameters into a
specific file at a specific spot because
it's just easier um through PHP.
Um
So, yeah, and then and then I also have
this other file called um like dreader
and then I've got a status code. So,
like dreader302.php,
right? And that takes a parameter that's
just like, you know, URL. So, whenever
I'm testing for SSRFs, I can always hit
that and then just pass into the URL
parameter um and it will just, you know,
create a dynamic redirect to wherever
I'm trying to go. Um and then I've got
those for 303, 301, 307, 308, all of the
redirect status codes. Um, I use those
all the time.
Nice.
I've also got like a sort of a callback
domain that I use for HTTP callbacks
that I've got set up um and it will just
ping me on Slack with the full HTTP body
um whenever it gets a hit. Um and so
I've been using that for like RCE
callbacks or SSRF callbacks. I want to
do something similar for DNS um but
obviously if somebody figures it out and
then starts spamming it, it's a little
bit annoying. So
Yeah. I'm curious do you run into like
Slack message limits and stuff? I
probably would use Discord for that now
because like Discord doesn't have
message limits and all that kind of
stuff.
Here's the thing, man. I I pay for it. I
I pay cuz I had I had I used to put all
of my I need to go back and I I've got
like let me just write some notes down
right here cuz I'm paying for way too
many things right now. He's like hold on
a second. This is a business expense.
It's like $107 a month I'm spending
here. So let me let me write that down.
Yeah, I need to Slack uh cancel Slack
and then DigitalOcean as well um because
yeah, I pay the $7 a month for Slack cuz
it's just single user, you know? So it's
like seven bucks. It's not a big deal.
Um but yeah, uh
but I can search, you know, all the way
back and pull out anytime you know, a
callback has hit, which is nice. Nice.
Um and then the other thing I'll mention
for my server uh go ahead. No, no, no,
go ahead. I was going to say the the the
thing the other thing I'll mention for
my VPS is that I will uh occasionally
use um whenever the PHP file isn't going
to cut it if I have like a more
complicated logic that I have to
articulate um in in you know, on an HTTP
server side, I will just go ahead and
set up like a reverse proxy in Apache um
and then just run like a Python HTTP
server on my you know, like Flask or
something like that on my on my
localhost and um
just have it proxy to that at a certain
path and then you know, I outline that
more complex exploitation logic in
there. Um I just feel like it's easier
to work with Python and I want
everything under you know, port 80 or
port 443. So thus I have the the reverse
proxy. Yeah, 100%. I mean, the whole
like wildcard thing and and all that
like reverse proxy and stuff, that's
another reason why I kind of like having
two boxes where um like I run a a
Traefik instance for all my like HTTP
routing and stuff. So I can do very
similar to like what you do. I can set
up a vhost that just points to like a
different file or a different port or
something or I can just handle it
separately or I can just point it to a
different IP address cuz I I have all of
I have a wildcard domain as well that I
can just set up, you know, whatever I
want. You can actually have a wildcard
as a as a catch all and then you can set
specific specific ones to point
elsewhere underneath that wildcard. I
don't know if you know that. I didn't I
didn't know that. Hmm.
Yeah, so you can have like
you know, star.example.com
go to something and then you can still
have like sub.example.com go to
something different than the wildcard
but the wildcard will catch everything
else. Yeah, you can.
Yeah, so that's pretty much what I do.
Very very very similar setup. Um and
like PHP, yeah, man.
Goat. It's like It's so simple, you
know? It's like what could be easier?
yeah. Yeah, it's like one step further
than Python. You know what I mean?
Because like you don't even need to spin
up like the server, you know, or
anything. You just do it in the file.
You just put it in
writing HTML, you know?
Yeah, exactly. I love it. Um simplicity
there is always good and and you know,
yeah, I think a lot of people have the
opinion that hackers are like and and
you know, we do get it on the edge of
technology and stuff like that. But
the the most important thing is that it
works and it works fast and that we can
iterate. This is This is just one of the
things that I mentioned on the podcast
before but I'll say it again. Shubz is
is just like hacking genius and and this
doesn't sound like that crazy but like
he told me once he's like, "Dude, just
write in whatever you can get you can
accomplish the goal in as fast as
possible, you know? Because at the end
of the day as a hacker, that's what
matters. You know, you don't have to
worry about optimizing this and that and
the other thing. Just get the product
out and I think that's a great a great
mentality as well from just like a
startup perspective is you want to prove
the value of the product before you
spend all the time, you know, hyper
engineering it. So
Right. just get something out there, get
something taped together, get it working
with bash and and
don't name stuff a.txt.
As long as you don't shoot yourself in
the foot with that one.
Maybe just like just a little
descriptive name. Yeah, or or you know,
just storing
what the mistake I've made as well is
storing like files that I'm actively
working on in temp. Oh, no. Yeah, that's
that's a mistake cuz if like your power
cuts or like you know, you restart your
computer on Windows update or something
like that, those
bye-bye. Yeah. See you later, temp
files. So um and and I sort of mentioned
this. I'll I'll just kind of tack this
on the end of the VPS thing. Um
python3-m
http.server is a command you can run to
just like spin up an HTTP server in your
current directory. Super duper helpful.
Um sometimes you just need to host a
file and you need to host a file quick
and Python's got your back on that. So
love that.
Yeah.
And I believe you can uh you can even
specify a port as an argument, right?
Yep, it's the next arg.
Yeah, the the first arg is it's the port
and then you can do dash dash bind and
you can set a bind IP too. So Hmm. Nice.
Yeah, that that is super useful. It just
opens in your your current folder. Use
that I use that all the time as well.
All right, let's see. Let's jump around.
Um you already talked about ffuf a
little bit there. So you can
take that one off the list. Um let's do
GoWitness. I I've I've used this one as
well but uh I might have a different
take. So go. All right. Yeah, so
GoWitness uh it's it's a screenshotting
tool. Um depending on what kind of recon
I'm doing, especially if I'm doing very
very large scale recon and especially on
websites that have a lot of duplication.
Um what I mean by that is like maybe
it's a wildcard domain uh that will
resolve to like a static landing page or
something, right? So you can probably do
a lot of this with curl and stuff but
with screenshots, it's kind of nice
because it's a visual representation.
One, it's super easy to review.
Uh so you could just like scroll
through. You could open 500 images. You
just scroll through and as soon as you
see something, go back. You'd be like,
"What is that?" And then you can load it
up and you can take a look. Um but one
thing I I like to do is I'll screenshot
a whole list of URLs and then I will run
either a sha sum a sha hash or an md5
hash on all the files and I will dedupe
them because the if it's a static
landing page, it actually screenshots
one-to-one identical, right? So that
means that if you have a bunch of the
same webpage that are under the same
subdomain, you can group them together
and you can put them in a folder by hash
that says, "Oh, okay, all these domains
are the exact same thing." Or like
visibly, they're visually identical.
Right? And then that will also help
narrow down those 500 images or whatever
that you've got down to maybe like 50 or
something.
Um so I I like to do that. It really
depends on what kind of recon I'm doing.
Generally for like larger scale recon,
that's what I'm going to be doing to
help filter stuff down so I can see what
stuff will would look interesting cuz
the way that I see it is if I'm going to
be reviewing this manually, I'm going to
take the list of domains I have. I'm
going to open them in my browser. I'm
going to look at them with my eyes. So
I'm going to do the exact same thing.
This just puts it all in one place that
I can review it quicker. Yeah. Yeah, and
that's important being able to to get a
visual look at at stuff as well. It can
really make some certain assets pop in
the sea of assets that is so many of
these organizations that we're looking
at. Um
I used GoWitness for a long time but one
of the things man, was it Aquatone or
was it GoWitness? One of one of the two
of them
um
they sent two HTTP requests for every
one that you
Yeah, I think it's GoWitness cuz it
checks HTTP and HTTPS. Well, it does
that but then the other thing is or I I
shouldn't say HTTP request. It's it
instantiates two TLS connections um and
one of them is to pull
uh is to do the HTTP request or HTTPS
request, right? And then the other one
is to pull the TLS certificate
information. Um and when I was really
this is probably showing how much of a
weirdo I was whenever I was doing my my
my recon stuff is I just totally like
fixated on that and I was like, "No,
this sucks. Like I cannot be sending two
I cannot have this overhead across, you
know, 5 million assets that I'm
monitoring. Um
so I actually uh read through like all
this crazy documentation and uh wrote a
script with headless Chrome to pull the
TLS certificate information and do the
HTTPS request in one request, which
actually seems like it should be pretty
doable but was hella difficult. Um and I
remember you know, I don't remember this
whole process and even though I'm
looking at the code right now, it's not
coming back to me super clear. But one
of the things that I do remember was
that like there was this uh gist that
some random dude like put out there that
just had like the keys to what I needed
for this. And then I went back to
reference it. I bookmarked it. I went
back to reference it like years later
and it's gone. And he deleted it. And I
was like, "How who just goes and deletes
that gist like that? Like what are you
doing, dude?" Um so at some point I'll
have to write write some of this up
because uh having that done in one one
piece, I think is is pretty it's it's
pretty nice from an efficiency
perspective. But
Nice. Yeah.
Nice. Super cool. All right, let's
Um what about p-prettier?
Okay, all right. Yeah, so this is
another big thing. You know, we talk
about Man, Joe, we're we're going long
on this episode already. All right, we
we thought this was going to be a quick
one but we we we we got to we got to get
back to the hacking, man. Yeah, yeah.
Uh yeah, so p-prettier um this is just
my go-to script for
um
uh JS beautification. So, you pass it a
JS file
and it does a really good job of
beautifying it and
it very rarely errors out, which is
nice. Um on some of the other ones, JS
Beautify and some of the others
Excuse me.
Um
does does that on a pretty regular basis
with complex JS files, but Prettier just
seems to do it Also, it's the P in
Prettier stands for
parallelization.
Something like that. Paralyzed
and so it's very fast and it uses
threads and that sort of thing.
So, great product there. Mixer made by
the Mixer team. Rip Mixer.
Um
Uh so, definitely check that out if
you're looking for some JS
beautification stuff. Okay. Uh
you Joel, I'm going to cross off all of
the mobile stuff on your Yeah,
that's been talked about.
We did a mobile episode
2 weeks ago. Yeah, hit us with the word
list stuff. This is just a good shout
out. Yeah, cool. So, word list, I mean,
listen, everybody's got their own word
list. Some people make their own, some
people just use all that txt, whatever
you want to use. The main ones that I
use, Jay Haddix's
uh
you know, all that txt and all the other
ones that he has.
Um the SecLists lists I really like and
AssetNote. The those lists I really
like. The AssetNote lists are built off
of big queries, so they're like
up-to-date, they're more like
current-ish, like, you know,
theoretically they're they're more like
positive hits on what's going on like
right now. Jay Haddix's just like, you
know,
everything.
And
and then the SecLists is kind of like
everywhere in between. There's some more
like refined word lists in there.
There's some some more variant options
if you want to target specific things,
words only, like the raft words. I like
that cuz those are just words and then
you can add extensions to them if you
want. Yeah, I like that, too.
That's helpful. So, yeah, that that's
word list. All right, cool. So, I'm just
going to look through here really
quickly so that we can wrap it up and
move to the reports.
Um
Yeah. So, you Masscan, we both have that
one.
have Masscan. Yeah, that's just crazy
fast port scanning.
That's it.
I've got DevTools on here as well and I
just wanted to mention a couple things
that I I've
noticed that people are struggling with
with the mentees that I'm working with
over the past couple weeks.
Um
So, inside of Dev inside of DevTools
when you open it up in Chrome, you'll
see right above your console input
there's a
a top
little drop-down, right? And it'll allow
you to select the context. I don't know
if there's a more a more specific word
for this. Yeah, no, it actually says
JavaScript context. Okay, if you hover.
Um you can select the context of where
this code is running. So, when you have
a page that has a bunch of iframes or
like inter-page communication, you want
to make sure that you are selecting the
correct context for your JavaScript code
to execute in
because otherwise you can get yourself
in some pickles with origin stuff and
and you know, thinking you have a bug
and you actually don't. Um
And this is also true, sort of,
on the on the sources tab as well.
There's some stuff that will only appear
when you have Let's see if I can find a
good example of this. I'm going to just
open up
Yeah, sources.
Um
There is No, I mean, this one doesn't
really have any either.
Let's see if this one does. Um yeah,
there's threads. That's the name of it
of what it's called in in sources. So,
if you open up a page,
there's will be different threads that
you can select within the browser and
this will automatically change the
context.
So, that's once again, I know we're in
audio medium here, but that's the
sources tab in DevTools on the
right-hand side, threads. Um and it's
only there if there are multiple threads
running. Um and so, sometimes selecting
those threads will actually get you
different results for stuff like the
global listeners tab and stuff like
that, which is where you enumerate your
um your listeners for that specific
page. Your post message listeners and
such. I've never seen that or maybe I've
never noticed it. What what website are
you using to to see that?
just have Twitter open. So, go just go
to Twitter and you're only going to see
like a service-worker.js.
Oh,
that's Okay, okay, okay. Yeah, yeah. Oh,
wow, I didn't even know you
could switch between the
can select the other thread and then,
you know, go to global listeners and go
to message and then sometimes there's
like additional post message listeners
there. And then you can also do this on
the left-hand side in the page
drop-down. If you select like a page
that has an iframe, you can go in there
and like select that specific frame and
that will update some stuff on the
right-hand side as well. Um so, don't be
missing out on some of the post message
listeners that are defined in the global
listener section of the sources tab in
DevTools just because you don't have the
correct tab selected or thread selected.
Kind of fiddle around with that, make
sure you you know what's what's going
on. And then also in the console area,
make sure you're selecting the correct
JavaScript context for your
code to be executing in to make sure
that there isn't some sort of implicit
a post message origin check or something
like that that's occurring
and it's just slipping by because you're
executing it in the context of the same
thing as the page rather than in like
your own domain or like the parent
domain. Yeah. So, good tips there.
Cool. Cool. Yeah, no, that that's a good
one.
Um okay.
So, we should talk about our command
line tools because you've got some cool
ones that I want to know about in yours,
but before we do that I'm going to
mention two things. Um one
uh
keyboard shortcuts. Um I have configured
Espanso um
it to like help me with some of my
automated typing stuff. So, essentially
you just type colon and then type like a
string and then it will automatically
replace it with you know, the string
that you want to. For example, I don't
have my server IP memorized and
sometimes I need the IP rather than the
DNS record. So, I'll type uh colon
server IP and it will just auto-fill in
my my server IP. And it does this at
like an input level on the keyboard, so
it works in lots of different
environments as well, which is really
cool.
That's really cool. I've never heard of
this and I do a lot of this with bash
scripts. So, like Do you really? I have
one called public IP. Like I have a bash
shortcut called public IP that does like
a dig. It does It calls a dig command
that returns your public IP and like
that's what I use for getting my public
IP. Yeah, and so you can actually call
out like in your Espanso configuration,
you can have it run shell commands and
then show the output. So, it like I've
got one for
colon EIP, external IP.
Which just makes a request to IP info
and pulls my external IP address that
I'm working from.
Um
So, that's that's a really cool one.
That's cool. Um and then the other thing
I have is keyboard shortcuts for things
like URL encoding, URL decoding, JSON
beautification, base64 encoding and
decoding, whatever is in my clipboard,
um which is extremely helpful when
you're trying to do stuff that's like
All right, now you
you know, URL decode it and then you
JSON beautify and then you modify it and
then you JSON minify it and then you URL
encode it and and you know, there's just
so much friction, but then like once you
have those things on a keyboard
shortcut, you can just go, you know,
control shift U, control shift I, you
know, and then you just kind of got that
muscle memory there and it start it
stops taking friction on your brain and
allows you to focus on the hacking.
Yeah. So, really I I literally I can't
tell you how much this has changed my
life like just having the keyboard
shortcuts for those sort of things.
Um
yeah, that's big. That that's super
neat. I use I use clipboard a lot as
well.
I rely on it. Sometimes I'll pipe in
bash, but more frequently what I'm
doing, I'm using a
IPython and IPython I just have it in
like a tab in my browser. Yeah, tell me
about that. And I have I have a little
script that I wrote, I call it PyHack,
and it's just like a bunch of little
shortcuts
that I'll tie back in. They'll basically
just be like aliases to other modules or
maybe like little definitions that call
a function within a module. And they'll
they'll do things like I have one for
hex encoding, base64 encoding and
decoding just on like literally the
keyword B64D. So, I'll type B64D, I'll
call it, and then I use a a module
called pyperclip, which is a it's a
cross-OS clipboard reading and writing
module. So, you just import from
pyperclip import copy and paste and then
those are two functions that you can
call to copy and paste to your
clipboard.
So, I'll do B64D paste and then it'll
print out whatever, you know, base64 or
I'll do copy B64D paste and then it'll
recopy whatever it decodes and I'll
chain those together very similar to to
what you're doing, but I'll just do it
in Python. Yeah, no, that's great. I was
wondering what IPython was cuz I use
Python a lot, but I don't you know, I
grew
up writing Python, so I always just
write it in a script and run it instead
of using some of these like IDEs. So, I
mean, is that just an IDE for Python?
No, so IPython it's a it's basically a
it's a REPL, right? It's just like an
interactive Python console. It's a
Jupyter notebook essentially. Um so, you
have access to like, you know, the
percent like Jupyter
type notebook type macros and stuff.
it's like yeah, okay. Yeah, but it's
like it's syntax highlighted, like new
lines. It's like a Python console, but
like functional, you know, it's like
usable. It has like, you know, syntax
highlighting and suggestions and
drop-downs and like colors and yeah, so
it's like it's really nice.
Good stuff. Yeah, I might have to check
that out at some point. I I I think a
lot of it's, you know, just kind of on
muscle memory for me already, but I
could, you know, integrate this
seamlessly. That'd be really helpful.
I mean, it's just like typing, right?
You find whatever works for you and then
if if you can do do faster than what
makes sense to like relearn it then
listen are you What are you saying,
Joel? You trying to like [__] on the
people that know how to like actually
type here? No, what I'm saying
I'm saying like Whatever works for you,
people that don't type with the What
Whatever works for you, hey, if you can
do it as fast or faster, then don't even
bother relearning it cuz it's probably
not worth it. Yeah. No, that makes
sense. Um so, definitely cool thing
there, keyboard shortcuts.
Um all right, let's talk about the
command line tools. Um so, like inside
of the base set,
let's see, where what is the overlap
here? We've both got said, we've both
got awk. sed, awk, jq, grep.
jq, grep, of course.
The trusty old database, grep. Yeah,
grep. Yeah, okay, grep, obviously
searching strings, you know,
it's just like, you know, you need to
search something within something else,
grep. Okay, if you want to do it with
regex, you you can either use egrep or
you can use rg, which is ripgrep, which
is like
Ripgrep is amazing.
Yeah, yeah, you put that on your list. I
probably should have put it on my list,
but it's it ripgrep it's I mean, you can
look at the speed test, the benchmarks
and stuff, but it's gre- it's way
faster. It's gre- it's written in Rust,
it's insanely fast, it has tons of
features. If I'm searching anything
remotely large, I'm using ripgrep cuz
it's way faster.
and I recently used this to just search
entire file systems. We we pulled a file
system off of a device, and then
literally just ripgrepped across the
whole file system for specific text. One
little tip, when you are using that,
don't forget the dash a parameter,
so that it doesn't ignore binary files.
Just like with grep, but so, yeah.
Ripgrep, super awesome. less, top, head
cut, you know, it's just like, you know,
things to view
large buffers of text without taking up
your entire terminal, or to search
within them. There's a lot of different
tools that do a lot of very similar
things that are built into Linux,
like head and
fzf
fzf, fuzzy find. So, fzf, it's an it's
an awesome tool, it's like an extension,
I think you like install it in your in
your shell. But basically, it adds two
main things, control r and control t.
Okay, I think you've mentioned this
before. Yeah, I think we talked about
this maybe off off air, but
basically like if you use control r in
your terminal, it'll let you reverse
search through your bash history, and
fuzzy
fuzzy find basically extends upon that.
So, it it lets you fuzzy find through
your bash history. So, if you don't
exactly type the exact command, it will
still search and it'll still show you
suggestions that roughly match,
basically getting fuzzier as it goes up.
And you can do the same thing for files
on the file system. So, if in your
current folder, you just control t or
you type fcf, it'll do the same exact
fuzzy search, but for files within your
current folder.
So, that's really useful for like
in in VS Yeah, exactly. Yep, control p,
your command palette or your your file
switcher in in Visual Studio Code. Very
very similar, it's really awesome, I use
it
multiple times a day every single day.
Um
In conjunction with that, zsh.
Uh that's my preferred shell.
I used bash for a while, it's pretty
good, I like zsh more. I don't really
know why, I think it's just more
customizable, I think it's more
friendly. I especially use oh my zsh
as as a you know, it's it's basically
just like a
a plugin like module thing that sits on
top of it that makes it easier to add
extensions, and then I use powerlevel10k
as my theme.
Nice. Yeah, no, that's awesome. I I
think those are all really essential
lists there. I know we're just kind of
rattling them off, but we should
probably like just
throw them into the description just so
people can know, you know, what kind of
command line tools they need to know
about.
will be one of those things you're going
to want to like sit at your computer,
you're going to we're going to read one
word, pause, go search it, like check it
out,
read another word, or yeah, we'll and
we'll try and put all all list of the
links in the in the show notes as well.
Solid. Okay, so this is the I've got two
more things here, and
uh one of them kind of flows into the
into the the report. So, I'll talk about
this one first. So, um
my life changed one day
uh in when when was it? Hold on, let me
see if I can
It was the at the I could The poster's
right over there. Unfortunately, I'm
blind, so I can't see it, but it was in
London.
Um I want to say it was 2019.
Sitting down there with Tom Nom Nom and
uh
Stoke at a live hacking event, and they
recorded this video.
And before they recorded this video, I
was sitting at this table with them, um
and essentially in the video, which I'll
link I'll link I keep on saying the
video, but
it's a video about Tom Nom Nom and Stoke
uh explaining bash for hackers, pretty
much. Um and one of the main things that
that Tom shows in this is like how to
use vim
as a tool to
manipulate input. And we were kind of
talking about like how if you get the
output from a tool and it's super large,
there's all these tools like, you know,
head and and less and top and and more
and those sort of thing that that allow
you to manipulate, you know, and and not
show the whole buffer on your screen and
just, you know, bomb your terminal.
Well, you can just pipe this stuff into
vim dash,
and it just throws it into a vim buffer,
and then, you know, you can just execute
additional commands by just
doing percent bang,
and you can just chain commands
together, and all of it's just in a vim
buffer, and you can search through it
easily, and it's just so so so nice. Um
and so, really, I I just this one this
one video that that um
Stoke and Tom Nom Nom put together
changed my efficiency on the command
line for the rest of my life. Like, I'm
still making gains on efficiency from
this. And so, definitely learn how to
use vim properly
to to, you know, limit your your buffer
that you're seeing and chain it through
different commands.
Yeah, I mean, vim is one of those tools
I learned how to use it back in college.
It was something I was super like averse
to originally. I was like a hardcore
nano user, you know, like it's always
it's like a it's a battle, you know,
hardcore nano user. Hardcore nano user,
yeah, there I don't think there really
are hardcore nano users, let's be
honest, right? So,
um I I tried out vim, and the thing
about vim, it's one of those things that
as you learn, the more that you learn,
the easier it gets, okay? Things you're
going to notice patterns that are very
common. Vim was written by programmers,
so it's like it's very systemic and
logical, you just have to understand the
logic systems that they're using, right?
It's just like
as most programs are. Yeah, you'll be
like, why do you like why if I press
like hjkl? Well, because touch typing,
right? It's like you have to think about
like, you know, and then if you
understand the the reasoning behind it,
it makes more sense. So, a lot of vim
can be confusing at first, but if you
take a little bit of time and you
understand the underlying reasons, it'll
make a lot more sense, and it'll make
your workflow significantly faster.
There are you're going to learn like
little keybinds. For example, okay,
here's one. If you're going to exit a
file, most people do either colon wq, or
maybe colon w then colon q. If you do
colon Yes, if you do colon lowercase x,
it will write if it needs to and exit.
No, you've got to be kidding me. Colon
lowercase x, just colon x. Yep.
vimtest.txt,
blahdy blahdy blah.
Lowercase x. What the heck?
Yep. And if there's no changes, it
doesn't write.
vim x makes perfect sense. It's the
thing you click on in the corner anyway.
Yeah, it does both. So, that's like a
super I I love that one, I use that one
all the time. Another one, this is like
really verbose, but basically, if you're
if if you've been in this situation
where you're editing a file, and you're
about to save it, and you realize I'm in
read-only mode, or I'm I didn't run this
with sudo, and I don't want to remake
these changes, okay? It's colon w space
bang sudo t
percent, okay? What?
And it basically it writes it, and then
it it runs sudo t as a command, and it
pipes it it pipes it back in. And then
it'll be like, do you want to reload the
file? And then you load it, and you're
good.
Well, wait, but what if you're in a
directory that doesn't
like you can't write.
Uh you would have to have sudo. So, like
a temp buffer or something?
I mean, you could change where it writes
to, instead of giving it percent, you
could just like
I'm sorry. We need to do I need to do
this right now. So, so, vim So, okay, so
let's say sudo
sudo su I I'm hopping into root. I'm
changing this I'm I'm changing the uh
permissions on this file.
test
And then I'm jumping out of root, and
try to write as test here. Can I write?
Okay, no, I I messed up my permissions.
Okay.
Okay, you know you know what? I'm not
even going to do this on air. Joel, we
have to you have to do this on
basically, all you have to know is that
col- like if you do colon w, and then
after that you do like space exclamation
point cat, for example, it will pipe
it'll write the current buffer to it'll
pipe it to that command, okay? So, it'd
be like if you have a all the stuff in a
file, and you like did
w exclamation cat, it would pipe the
stuff from the file into cat, okay? So,
similarly,
you can pipe that into sudo t,
like the t command, t e e, to append
stuff to a file, right? And percent in
vim is the current is the file name
that's associated with a buffer. So,
you're saying pipe the current buffer
into sudo t file name,
and then
that's how you're actually writing it
with sudo, and then after you write
that, vim will be like, hey, the file
was modified, do you want to reload it?
And you'll click yes, and then it'll
have your changes there. And then you
can just quit.
No way. Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Hold on. I've got my
I've got I so I've got my test
environment up. So I can't write. It
says read only. And I pipe it into sudo
t
percent percent
Yep.
And that'll be your current file. If you
don't have a file, then you could just
put your file where percent is.
What the heck?
My life is changed.
Pretty dope. Dude, I run into this [__]
all the time. That makes so much sense.
I don't know why I didn't cuz I always
what what I always end up doing is end
up like sudo or or end up writing it to
like temp and then like getting out,
sudo-ing, then copying it from temp back
to where it is. This happens all the
time when I'm trying to modify my my
Apache uh you know, configuration or
Yeah, you forget to write it with sudo.
You make a bunch of changes and then you
got to undo it and start over and
Wow, life-changing life-changing things
being dropped on this episode, man. Joe,
I think we need to just sit down
sometime and like I just need to like
Joe, tell me things that I don't know
about the technologies that I use every
day cuz that is that is really helpful.
Okay.
Um okay, yeah, we're at like an hour 10.
Dude, there is no short episode with us.
Yeah, no. I mean, this one is like
really hard because there's like so much
nuance to all these tools and I think
it's it's important to understand. Um
like the thing that I explained with
Vim, right? Like that that is a perfect
example of understanding like what
you're doing, right? Instead of just
like blindly like copy-pasting like
colon w exclamation right? Like what is
it doing? Oh, it's writing the buffer.
It's piping it into a command. It's
using t percent means the file name. Now
I get it. Now I could do that for
anything else. I could change it with
other commands. I can, you know, use
this functionality anytime I run another
Vim command. So you just have to
understand the fundamentals and then
that that that really helps a lot.
That's great.
Um okay, so I'm going to jump into the
next one and then I'm going to take that
right into the report section. So the
next one that I wanted to talk about was
DNS Chef. Uh this is a tool that uh Mr.
Tux Racer uh introduced to me a while
back. Um it's essentially a tool that
allows you to just kind of run a DNS
server on the fly and you can like spoof
DNS records. You can uh get DNS
callback. So like for example, if you're
trying to do a DNS callback that doesn't
go through collaborator, um then you can
do it through um DNS just like set your
own domain, set your VPS as the
authoritative name server for that, you
know, section of your domain, spin up
DNS Chef, run it on port four or on port
53, and then you'll get the the DNS
callback there. And um
so I was trying to find some reports
that were using some of the tools here.
And obviously, a lot of the tools that
we're talking about here just kind of
workflow tools. Yeah, it's like all my
reports use these tools. Like I use them
all the time. Exactly. Vim is in every
single report that I write now. Um but
DNS Chef was one of the ones that
actually like had a pretty tangible
result. And
um it was a pretty weird program that I
reported a bug to with this. And
essentially, what the program wanted to
do was they wanted to check and see
whether we could establish a reliable
um
reverse shell or a
reliable shell of any kind
um inside of their VDI environment that
they had set up. Um and there was a very
stringent set of rules for
like uh
the
servers you could communicate with over
HTTP HT and HTTPS. So it was kind of
tricky. And we found a couple ways to do
it. Um
tip, there's a proxy that you can use
inside of Google. So if any of the
Google services you are using, you can
use translate to uh the Google translate
service to uh open up a a page inside of
Google translate.
taking me back to like computer hacking
when I was like a a preteen. Yeah.
Exactly. This is like how you get around
your school like exactly the the the web
filter. Yeah. Exactly. So that was one
way that we were able to do it. Um
another way we were able to do it was uh
by a a DNS shell. And instead of using
like some of the all this crazy stuff
out there, I said, "You know what? I'm
going to take 5 minutes." It ended up
taking like 2 hours um to write my own
little DNS shell here. But it would have
taken a lot longer if DNS Chef wasn't
around cuz um it just makes it really
easy to hook into
uh if you read the code, it's there's a
pretty clear spot to hook into it and
handle a um
TXT request uh DNS TXT request. Um and
and so I just wrote like a little
20-line client on the client side that
like pings the server for a command,
runs the command, gets the output, hex
encodes it, and then sticks it in a DNS
request back out to my server. Um and
made made that little um you know,
reverse DNS reverse shell uh within
Python. And that fulfilled the
requirements and got got us the bounty
for um you know, establishing a reliable
shell outside of their
VDI environment. Um so I think sometimes
the takeaway here is just kind of like
you got to you know, Joe, I know you're
an avid listener of my first million as
well. Um love that podcast. Um but one
of the things they say on there is just
do cool [__] you know, like just find
the stuff that's cool and then do that,
right? And and and then do it. Yeah. And
I think this is one of those things for
me though is just kind of like, okay, I
would like to be able to write a a DNS,
you know, reverse shell um in in Python.
And so took some time, did it, got the
cool bounty for it. And I always try to
go down those routes whenever I see
these goals that people set up. Uh we
talked about for example, um breaking
out of root detection. Like you know
that that's going to be possible because
you control the app with Frida. So you
should always be able to break out of uh
you know, root detection. So doing
something like that and doing something
like this uh where they like guarantee
bounties for things that you know are
possible, um you know, just go and do it
and it gets you a lot more deeper
understanding of some of these things
that you know are are possible on the
border. So Yeah. Yeah, I I think it's
like that perfect perfect combination
between like CTF kind of like hack the
box like training type of stuff and real
world like get a bounty for what you're
doing because it's it's you're combining
real world with a challenge, right? Like
you see the challenge, all you have to
do, solve the challenge, right? Okay.
Well,
you have you know the constraints,
you're within this environment, figure a
way out.
So yeah, I I love those types of things.
Yeah, same. And and yeah, that mixes
well with your puzzler
puzzler Yeah, that tickles my puzzle
brain really hard.
Um all right, man. I think that's that's
it. Um
I guess I know we were planning on
talking about some some hardware hacking
stuff at the end of this episode, but
let's push that to a different episode.
Um and we'll, you know, more deep deep
dive it cuz I've got some really cool
like tools you're teaching me how to use
like right over here. And I'm excited to
get on the pod and talk about those. So
we'll do that a different time. Super
awesome. All right, catch you next week.
Sweet. That's the pod. See you.
Yo, thanks for listening to this episode
of Critical Thinking Bug Bounty podcast.
If you wanted to, you could go over to
Twitter @ctb podcast and give us a
follow or maybe even subscribe
@criticalthinkingpodcast
on YouTube. But the thing that would
make you the real MVH would be simply
just telling your friends and hacker
fellows about the pod. Word of mouth is
one of the biggest ways that podcast
grow, so spread the word. Thanks. See
you next week.